Finding Aid for Museum of Art (University of Michigan) Publications, 1946-ongoing
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  This series also contains bibliographies and brochures created by the various generations of the Museum Practice Program. These include the Graduate Program in Museum Practice, Program in Museum Practice, and Seminar in Museum Practice. They are all filed together under the heading "Museum Practice Program." There are exhibition catalogs (1965-1991 and 1993) for exhibits produced as a graduation requirement for the program's students. These are arranged chronologically. There is also a history The Graduate Program in Museum Practice and the Museum Seminars: The First Twenty Years, written in 1979 by Charles Sawyer and published in 1980. This history is a memoir of the founder of the program.
  - Chamber Concerts
    - Flyers 1991-1996 (Box 12)
    - Programs 1992-1998 (Box 12)
    - Schedules 1991-1997, undated (Box 12)
  - Connoisseurs Club
    - Flyers undated (Box 12)
    - Invitations 1990-1993, undated (Box 12)
  - Development
    - Brochures
      - A Heritage of Leadership at the Museum of Art, [1983] (Box 12)
    - Flyers 1986-1989, undated (Box 12)
    - Invitations 1978-1997, undated (Box 12)
  - Docents Programs
    - Directories 2002-2003 (Box 12)
    - Flyers undated (Box 12)
    - Guided Tours 1993-1994, undated (Box 12)
    - Histories
      - A Docent Journey, 1995 (Box 12)
      - Perspectives: The University of Michigan Museum of Art Docents on Favorites from the Collection, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Invitations 2001-2002 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters 1993 (Box 12)
    - Reports
      - A Profile of the University of Michigan Museum of Art Docent Program, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Doris Sloan Memorial Lecture
    - Invitations 1989-1999 (Box 12)
    - Programs 1990-1993, 1999-2001 (Box 12)
  - Family and Children's Art Museum Program (ChAMP)
    - Brochures 1991-1993, undated (Box 12)
    - Flyers undated (Box 12)
    - Schedules undated (Box 12)
  - Friends of the University of Michigan Museum of Art
    - Brochures
      - Membership 2000, undated (Box 12)
    - Exhibition Catalogs (Art and Antique Auction)
      - The Automobile as Art: Our Culture in Motion, 1993 (Box 12)
      - The Fine Art of Discovery Art and Antique Auction, 1987 (Box 12)
      - In Search of Serendipity, 1983 (Box 12)
    - Flyers
      - Membership Activities 1974-1992 (Box 12)
    - Invitations 1975-1995, undated (Box 12)
    - Newsletters
      - Friends, 1980-1984, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Friends' Newsletter, 1985-1989, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Friends of the University of Michigan Museum of Art Newsletter, 1968, 1970-1972 vol. 1-4, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Special Programs
      - Art and Antique Auction and Sale 1983 (Box 12)
      - Birthday Celebration 1976 (Box 12)
      - Collector's Seminar Series 1993-1995, undated (Box 12)
      - Jazz at the Museum 1973 (Box 12)
      - Lecture Series undated (Box 12)
      - Renaissance Week 1975 (Box 12)
      - Shopping Day undated (Box 12)
  - International Travel Program
    - Brochures 1984, 1993-1998 (Box 12)
  - Museum Practice Program
    - Bibliographies
      - Bibliography for Conservation of Museum Collections, 1974 (Box 12)
      - Selective Bibliography on Museums and Museum Practice: Museums of Art and History in the United States, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Brochures
      - General 1971, undated (Box 12)
    - Bulletins 1963, 1971, undated (Box 12)
    - E-mail (printouts) 2003 (Box 12)
    - Exhibition Catalogs
      - James Marshall Plumer Memorial Collection, December 6, 1964-January 10, 1965 (Box 12)
      - Reflections: The Image of Man, December 5, 1965-January 16, 1966] (Box 12)
      - Twentieth Century American and European Drawings, [December, 1966] (Box 12)
      - Japanese Prints: Traditions in Costume, December 2, 1967-March 3, 1968 (Box 12)
      - English Revivalism, 1750-1870 The Aesthetic of Nostalgia, [ca. 1968] (Box 12)
      - John Mix Stanley: A Traveler in the West, December 7, 1969-January 18, 1970 (Box 12)
      - Chinoiserie: Fantasy in the Age of Reason, December 6,1970- January 17, 1971 (Box 12)
      - Rome Through the Eyes of the Eighteenth Century, December 5, 1971-January 16, 1972 (Box 12)
      - Albert Kahn: Architect Abroad, December 10, 1972-January 14, 1973 (Box 12)
      - Bauhaus, December 9, 1973-January 27, 1974 (Box 12)
      - Reflections of an Era of Change: The Art of France, 1774-1830, March 12-April 6, 1975 (Box 12)
      - Pompeii as Source and Inspiration: Reflections in Eighteenth-and Nineteenth-Century Art, April 7-May 15, 1977 (Box 12)
      - Art a la Carte: Decorative Imagery in Maps, 1600-1800, [April 20, 1979] (Box 12)
      - Paris and the American Avant-Garde, 1900-1925, September 19-November 2, 1980 (Box 12)
      - African Images: Art and Ornament, April 3-August 9, 1981 (Box 12)
      - Margaret Watson Parker: A Collector's Legacy, March 20-April 26, 1982 (Box 12)
      - Forest, Prairie, and Plains: Native American Art from the Chandler/Pohrt Collection, March 19-May 22, 1983 (Box 12)
      - Trends and Traditions in Japanese Art, March 23-June 10, 1984 (Box 12)
      - Earth Magicians: Pottery from the Collections of the University of Michigan, March 29-June 16, 1985 (Box 12)
      - Signs and Seats of Power, April 20-July 27, 1986 (Box 12)
      - From Seed-Time to Harvest, April 12-May 31, 1987 (Box 12)
      - Rites of Spring: Passing Moments, Eternal Cycles, April 8-May 30, 1988 (Box 12)
      - All Creatures Great and Small, March 31-May 21, 1989 (Box 12)
      - Grounded: Sculpture on the Floor, April 7-June 3, 1990 (Box 12)
      - Greece vs. Rome: The Search for the Classical Spirit, March 16-April 28, 1991 (Box 12)
      - An Eighteenth-Century Moment: The Legacy of Charles Sawyer, March 13-May 16, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Histories
      - The Graduate Program in Museum Practice and the Museum Seminars: The First Twenty Years, 1980 (Box 12)
    - Invitations 1988 (Box 12)
    - Newsletters 1983 (Box 12)
  - New Art League
    - Press Releases 1995 (Box 12)
  - Thirtieth Anniversary Project Committee
    - Exhibition Catalogs
      - Daedalus, [1976] (Box 12)